好啦  节目马上开始直播  大家拿出最佳表现  精神点
All right, we're about to go live.Everyone on their A-game!Good energy!
大家好
Hello.
我是谢尔顿·库珀博士
I'm Dr. Sheldon Cooper.
我是艾米·菲拉·福勒博士
And I'm Dr. Amy Farrah Fowler.
欢迎收看特殊回忆集
And welcome to a special retrospective,
我们将回顾《有趣的旗帜》这一节目的起源
where we will take a look back at the history of Fun with Flags
请收看这一集...
on an episode we're calling...
《有趣的旗帜:  旗帜背后回忆特辑》
Fun with Flags: Behind the Flags: A Retrospective.
♪ 好奇节目如何开始 ♪
♪ Wondering how it all began ♪
♪ 得超长待机不打盹 ♪
♪ You'll need a good attention span ♪
♪ 无论知识还是娱乐 ♪
♪ For information and entertainment ♪
♪ 这个节目统统都有 ♪
♪ That's equally effective ♪
♪ 有趣旗帜 旗帜背后 回忆特辑 ♪
♪ It's fun with flags,behind the flags.A retrospective ♪
♪ 旗开得胜 ♪
♪ Flags. ♪
提醒大家  我们说旗帜"背后"
Mind you, when we say behind the flags
不是指这两面旗帜的背后  它们背后是我们的餐桌
we don't literally mean these flags.That's just where we have dinner.
好了  我相信你们很多人都好奇《有趣的旗帜》是如何开始的
Now, I'm sure many of you are wondering how Fun with Flags began.
让我们听听见证我们节目开始的  老朋友们怎么说
So let's hear from some people who were there at the very start.
霍华德  记忆闪回音效
H-Howard. Flashback sounds.
-明明我用竖琴也能弹  -你乖乖播影片就对了
-Could have played that on my harp.  -Just roll the clip.
用你们自己的话告诉大家《有趣的旗帜》开始时那魔力的瞬间
So tell us in your own words about that magical moment when Fun with Flags was born.
说真的  我记不得了
I honestly don't remember.
你肯定记得
Sure you do.
我当时正跟你们俩说
I was telling you both the story
海地与列支敦士登两国是怎么发现与对方用了同样的国旗
about how Haiti and Lichtenstein discovered they had the same flag.
当时正值1936年的夏季奥运会
It was at the Summer Olympics of 1936,
这两个勇敢的国家
and two plucky nations...
等等  我想起来了
Oh, wait. I remember.
那你还记得当时对我说什么了吗
Oh, and do you remember what you said?
记得  拜托去找愿意鸟你的人
Yes. Please find someone who cares.
于是我真的这么做了
And that's exactly what I did.
我找到了很多愿意鸟我的人
I found a lot of someones.
有将近两百人呢
Almost 200.
很多人还是强迫中奖
Many of them on purpose.
现在我们要听听你们怎么说  各位观众
And now we're going to turn it over to you, the viewers,
请踊跃来电分享你们最喜爱的节目时刻
to call in and share your favorite Fun with Flags moments.
如果发现电话占线  千万别气馁  继续尝试拨打就对了
And-and don't get discouraged if the phone lines are jammed.Just keep trying.
老天保佑  欢迎致电《有趣的旗帜》
Oh, thank God! Welcome to Fun with Flags!
你好  谢尔顿  你好啊  艾米  是我伯特
Hey, Sheldon. Hey, Amy. It's Bert.
你好啊  伯特  你有什么跟旗帜有关的评语或疑问呢
Hello, Bert. What is your flag-related comment or query?
我交到女朋友了
I have a girlfriend.
这跟旗帜有什么关联呢
And what does that have to do with flags?
没关联  我就是想告诉大家我交到女朋友了
Nothing. I just wanted everyone to know I have a girlfriend.
伯特  你别占着线路了
All right, Bert, you're tying up the line.
在此跟试图打进来分享与旗帜有关评论的各位道歉
My apologies to all of you trying to call in with legitimate flag comments.
好的  下一位观众打进来了
All right. W-We have our next caller.
她的名字叫丽贝卡
Her name's Rebecca.
第十季  第二十一集
我们是先去吃饭  还是在动物园里吃
Should we get lunch or you want to eat at the zoo?
华仔  我不用吃饭  我玩手机就能玩饱
Oh, Howie, I don't need food as long as I can look at my phone.
我不喜欢你模仿我
I don't like when you imitate me.
那你想听我模仿斯图尔特吗
You want to hear my Stuart?
我有好一阵子没跟人约会过了
It's been a while since I've gone on a date.
不介意看一下猴子交配吧
You mind if we watch the monkeys doing it?
这是我私下跟你说的好吗
I said that to you in confidence.
这应该是我们的家庭欢乐游
This is supposed to be our family fun day.
你手机上有什么事那么重要
What's so important on your phone?
我在看托儿所的网站
I'm on the day care's Web site.
不用看了
Stop looking at that.
那家托儿所很赞  就在我校区里
The day care's great. It's on campus.
离我办公室就两分钟路程  没什么好担心的
My office is two minutes away. There's nothing to worry about.
万一她对托儿所员工的喜爱胜过我们怎么办
What if she likes the people who work there more than us?
她对肥皂泡泡的喜爱已经胜过我们了
She already likes soap bubbles more than us.
一旦我回去工作  我们就要把她交到这些人手里
When I go back to work,we're gonna leave her with these people.
而我们完全不了解他们
We don't know anything about them.
他们都是通过背景调查  训练有素的教育工作者
They're highly-trained educators with background checks.
甚至要求身上所有疫苗皆要在有效期内
They're even required to be current on all vaccinations.
你也让我照顾她啊  可刚才说的我一样都没有
You leave her with me, and I'm not any of those things.
霍华德人呢
Where's Howard?
他请一天假
He took the day off.
那我们快把握他不在的机会
Oh, let's take advantage of his absence
多说一点只有我们物理学家才懂的笑话
and tell the kinds of jokes only physicists get.
我先来
I'll go first.
来  听好了  有天德国物理学家海森堡开车被警察拦下
Okay, here.Uh, Heisenberg is pulled over by a police officer.
警察对他说  你知道你刚才开到了时速137公里吗
And the policeman says,did you know you were going 85 miles per hour?
然后海森堡说  靠  现在我不知道我在哪里了
And Heisenberg says, darn it, now I don't know where I am.
海森堡曾提出过不确定性原理
表明"粒子的位置与动量不可同时被确定"
霍华德周一回来是吗
So Howard back Monday?
对
Yeah.
-伙计们  -你好
-Hey, guys.  -Oh, hello.
-嘿  -要坐下来一起吃吗
-Hey.  -Want to join us?
可他是个地质学家  而我还有很多物理笑话要讲呢
But he's a geologist, and I have more physics jokes.
快请坐
Oh, quick! Sit!
谢尔顿说你交了新的女朋友
So, Sheldon says you have a new girlfriend.
对啊  他在我旗帜节目上无礼地宣布这消息
Yeah, which he rudely announced on my flag show.
人们对此超级不爽的
People were so upset about it
以致于当晚后来再也没有人打电话进来
no one else called in the rest of the night.
抱歉  我克制不住自己
Sorry. I couldn't help myself.
大概我只是太爱爱情
I guess I just love love.
我为你感到由衷高兴
Well, I'm very happy for you.
我们今晚一起吃晚餐  不如你们俩也加入我们吧
Hey, we're all having dinner tonight. Why don't the two of you join us?
是啊  等一下  我们对这个女人一点都不了解
Yeah, wh-- Hold on. We don't know anything about this woman.
你想了解什么
What do you want to know?
她是地质学家吗
Is she a geologist?
-不是  -很好  晚上7点见
- No. - Oh, great. See you at 7:00.
我们看完这个就去看奇珍异鸟表演怎么样
How about after this we go see the exotic bird show?
这主意不好  我的头发是鸟类梦寐以求的筑巢材料
Not a good idea. My hair is a coveted nesting material.
有学到什么吗
Learning anything?
树懒宝宝一直粘着妈妈不松手  这过程差不多有一年
Well, sloth babies cling to their mothers' bodies for almost a year.
而我在短短的四个月后就要回去工作了
I'm going back to work after only four months,
所以我学到我恨我自己  我恨树懒
so I've learned I hate myself, I hate sloths,
我恨你把我带来这里
and I hate you for bringing me here.
你恨我我懂  可那只树懒还挺可爱的
Me I get, but that sloth is pretty cute.
不仅仅是树懒
It's not just the sloth.
北极熊喂养幼熊的时间也差不多有八个月
Polar bears nurse their cubs for almost eight months.
母猩猩每天晚上都给她的宝宝弄个新窝
The orangutan mother builds her baby a new home every night.
而我呢  我选择了事业  舍弃了孩子
And what do I do? I choose my career over my child!
早跟你说我们应该去乐高乐园
Told you we should have gone to Legoland.
真不敢相信伯特都有女朋友了  而我却没有
Can't believe Bert has a girlfriend and I don't.
我还以为你要在花丛中歇歇脚  好好专注你的事业
I thought you were taking a break from women to focus on your career.
成熟点好吗
Oh, grow up.
你没有朋友可以介绍给他了吗
Don't you have any friends he can date?
我已经把伯纳黛特介绍给霍华德了
Hey, I already set up Howard and Bernadette.
该轮到你去毁掉某个可怜妹子的人生了
It's your turn to ruin some poor girl's life.
-你们好呀  请进  -谢谢
-Oh, hey, guys. Come in.  -Thanks.
各位  这位是丽贝卡
Everyone,this is Rebecca.
-嗨  - 嗨，你好
-Hi.  -Hi. Hello.
她不但比他年轻  长得还比他好看千百倍
She's younger and far more attractive than he is.
他们俩在模仿你们俩呢
They're copying you two.
你在做什么
What are you making?
鸡肉  鸟儿蹂躏我的头发  我得加倍蹂躏它们同类
Chicken. Birds mess with my hair, I come back hard.
哈雷终于睡下了吗
Finally get Halley down?
是的  终于
Yeah, eventually.
不过她还是很抗拒用奶瓶喝奶
She's still not happy about taking a bottle, though.
如果你没准备好回去上班
Look, if you're not ready to go back to work,
我们会想到解决办法的
we'll figure something out.
算了  我会没事的
No, I'll be fine.
这对哈雷来说或许是好事
It might be good for her.
霍华德他妈就一直陪在他身边
Howard's mother was around him all the time,
结果把他惯成世界级的妈宝
and he's a world-class mama's boy.
你为什么要这么说
I mean, wh-why would you say that?
来啊  发脾气啊  那恰恰证明我是"错"的
Go ahead, have a tantrum; that'll prove me wrong.
其实把哈雷养育成比你更独立的人也没什么不好啊
It would be nice to raise Halley to be a little more independent than you were.
大概吧
I guess.
我到了上大学才知道  原来可以用最嘴量体温
It wasn't until college that I learned you can put a thermometer in your mouth.
听完这么有趣的事  晚餐也好了
On that charming note, dinner is served.
这是你第一次跟科学家约会吗
So is this your first time dating a scientist?
因为我打算弄一个互助团
'Cause I'm thinking of starting a support group.
其实我不是第一次了  我曾跟一名科学神教信徒订婚
Actually, I'm not new to this.I was engaged to a Scientologist.
科学神教是一个争议颇大的"宗教"
教主曾是科幻小说家  与科学并无关联
伯特  丽贝卡  我要为我之前无心说错的话道歉
Bert, Rebecca.I'd like to apologize for my insensitive comment earlier.
别担心  没关系啦
Don't worry about it. It's fine.
瞧  人家说没关系  我不用出门思过
See? It was fine.I didn't need a time-out.
不是真的出门思过  我们吃东西吧
It wasn't a time-out. Let's get some food.
你让我出门坐在楼梯上  悔过自己的所作所为
You made me sit on the stairs and think about what I did.
去拿吃的
Get your food!
-你们俩怎么认识的  -嗯
-So how did you two meet?  -Yeah.
这是一个有爱的故事
Oh, it's such a cute story.
我们在一个约会网站上认识的
We met on a dating Web site.
就这样吗
Is that it?
抱歉  全剧终
Oh, sorry. The end.
挺好的  我在网络交友这方面还从未成功过
That's nice. I haven't had much success meeting people online.
我也是  直到我修改了我的个人档案
I didn't either, until I revamped my profile.
你做了什么  删掉自己的照片吗
What'd you do, delete your photo?
-出去  -好吧
- Go. - Fine.
你敢摔门试试
And don't you slam that door.
可恶
Aw, man.
我说错什么了吗
Did I say something wrong?
不  说错话的永远是他
No, it's always him.
伯特  你刚说到你更新了自己的个人档案
So, Bert, you were telling us how you updated your profile?
对  之前没有一个人理我
Right. I wasn't getting any responses,
然后我加了一条  最近刚获得天才奖与奖金62.5万美元
and then I added, recent $625,000 MacArthur grant winner.
结果五分钟后
and five minutes later,
我就遇到了我的灵魂伴侣
I met my soul mate.
是我错了  你可以进来了
I was wrong. You can come back in.
丽贝卡  你是怎么当上私人健身教练的呢
So, Rebecca, how did you become a personal trainer?
我来洛杉矶是想成为演员  但结果并不尽如人意
I came to Los Angeles to be an actress,and things didn't really work out.
我本来想说她又在模仿你  可是...
I'd say she's copying you again, but...
我真的不想再被赶出门外
...I'm getting tired of sitting in the hall.
我很需要一个私人健身教练
I'd love a personal trainer.
我下班路上开了一家网红奶昔店后  从此腹肌是路人
I haven't seen my abs since they opened a Shake Shack on my drive home.
我可以免费给你上几堂课
I could give you some free sessions.
听者有份吗
Oh, is that offer for everybody?
省省吧  我不会去的
Nice try. I'm not going.
-洗手间在哪里  -就在里面
-Where's your bathroom?  -Mm, just down there.
她真的太完美了  有时我都怀疑她不是真人
She's so perfect, sometimes I think she isn't real.
直到她去上厕所  我才能确定她是真人
And then she goes to the bathroom, and I know she is.
真的好甜蜜好诡异哦
Aw, that's so weird.
恕我直言  伯特  你不担心她和你在一起只是为了钱吗
I'm sorry, Bert, but aren't you worried she's only with you for your money?
就希望她是啊
She better be.
我们第一次约会  我就给她买了一台80寸的平板电视
On our first date, I bought her an 80-inch flat-screen.
第一次约会就买了  你有量过她家电视墙有多大吗
Your first date?  Did you even measure her walls?
我们第一次约会时  莱纳德用折价券给我买了椒盐脆饼
You know, on our first date,Leonard used a coupon to buy me a pretzel.
从此我们就过上了幸福快乐的生活
And we lived happily ever after.
全剧终
The end.
-我准备出门了  -祝你复工第一天愉快
-Well, guess I'm ready to go.  -Have a great first day back.
托儿所要用到的你都给她准备好了吗
You have everything she needs for day care?
好了  都装到包包里了
Yep, all in the bag.
很好
Good.
好了  宝宝  妈妈要去上班了  你今天玩得开心哦
Okay, sweetie,Mommy's gonna go to work now, so you have fun today.
我跟她说了  如果托儿所跟监狱情况一样
I told her if day care is anything like prison,
那就去把最大只的宝宝打晕就对了
find the biggest baby and knock him out.
再见  小可爱  我会想你的
Bye, cutie.I'm gonna miss you.
我今晚会在家里等着你回来
I'm gonna be waiting right here tonight when you get home.
别这样  你害得我都想哭了
Stop, you're gonna make me cry.
这下好了  现在大家都哭了
Great, now everybody's crying.
至少哈雷没哭啊
At least Halley's not.
那很好啊
That's good.
她一整天都见不到我们  而她根本不在乎
She's not gonna see us all day, and she doesn't even care!
准备好要被逗乐了吗
Who's ready to laugh?
开讲啦
Okay. So...
费曼  爱因斯坦和薛定谔一同走进酒吧里
Feynman, Einstein and Schrodinger walk into a bar.
费曼说  看样子我们身处一个笑话里
Feynman says,It appears we're inside a joke.
爱因斯坦回答  但仅仅是对看见我们一起走进来的人而言[相对论]
Einstein replies, but only to an observer who saw us walk in simultaneously.
薛定谔对他说道  如果有人从窗户望进来观察  我就立马走人
To which Schrodinger says,if someone's looking in the window, I'm leaving.
薛定谔的猫这实验中  如果实验者观察[酒吧]内部
可发现一只死猫[人]或活猫  而非又死又活的叠加态
其实还挺好笑的
That's actually funny.
你应该把这笑话发给脱口秀主持人
You should send that to Jimmy Fallon.
-嘿  -你好
-Hey. -Hello.
-嘿 伯特  -一起坐吧
-Hey,Bert.Yeah.  -Join us.
抱歉啊  昨晚气氛有点尴尬
Hey, sorry if last night was awkward.
事实上  我开始思考  我不应该用炫富的方式换取爱情
Actually, it got me thinking that I shouldn't flaunt my money to find love.
我可能会跟丽贝卡分手
I might break up with Rebecca.
这是个很重大的决定
Wow, that's a big step.
这很能表现出你高尚的品德
I think it shows a lot of character.
我要等等看  看看会不会有年轻性感的金发妞单纯喜欢我这个人
I'm gonna hold out and see if I can find a hot young blonde who likes me for me.
这笑话真好笑
That's a good one.
莱纳德  轮到你说笑话了
Okay, now, Leonard, you tell a joke.
-她还好吗  -她很开心  你看
-How's she doing?  -She's great.Hey look.
我看到墙  地板
I see a wall...floor...
某个亚洲娃
some Asian baby...
看到她了
There she is.
看到没  没什么好担心的
See? Nothing to worry about.
谢谢  好了  我得试着处理工作了
Thank you. Okay, I'm gonna try and get some work done.
好  我也是  爱你
Yeah, me, too. Love you.
我也爱你  再见
Love you, too. Bye.
她怎么样了
How is she?
你在这里干嘛
What are you doing here?
一个男人就不能到一所他没读过的大学
Can't a guy hang out at a college he doesn't go to
盯着看一个不是他生的宝宝吗
and stare at a baby that isn't his?
我能理解  我都没走到办公室就忍不住来看她了
I get it.I haven't even made it to my office yet.
如果我们一整天就站在这看她  会不会很怪
Is it weird if we just stand here and watch her all day?
大概会吧
Probably.
我们该走了
We should go.
是啊
Yeah.
又或者我们可以带她去水族馆
Or we could take her to the aquarium.
我去抱她  你去拿她的包包
I'll get her, you grab her bag.
撑住  哈雷  我们来救你出来了
Hang on, Halley, we're busting you out of there!
你在看什么
What are you looking at?
在看《旗帜背后回忆特辑》的评论
Comments from our Behind the Flags retrospective.
听听这个  有人夸这一期为至今最漫长的一集
Get this, people are calling it the longest one yet.
有人在家吗
Hello? Anybody home?
是伯特吗
Is that Bert?
是伯特
It's Bert.
我觉得好像是伯特
I think it's Bert.
怎么了
Hey, what's up?
我和丽贝卡分手了
I broke up with Rebecca.
这对你来说是好事呀
Oh...Well, good for you.
才怪  我想死她了
No, I miss her.
我不懂当时为什么要听你的
I don't know why I listened to you.
他说得没错
He's not wrong.
都是你瞎扯什么他值得被爱
It was your crackpot idea that he deserves love.
下次你想说话时  必须先举手
You know, you need to start raising your hand before you speak.
是的  从现在开始
Yes, starting now.
伯特  你是个好人  你值得被一个爱你
Bert, you're a good guy; you deserve a woman
而不是只爱你的钱的女人爱
who's interested in more than just your money.
她也爱只穿着小裤裤在我家溜达
She was also interested in walking around my house in her underwear.
现在家里会这样的人只有我了
Now the only one doing that is me.
如果你这么难过  就把她追回来吧
If you're that upset, go get her back.
我试过了  她都不接我的电话了
I tried.She's not answering my calls.
一想到电话还是我买给她的  就心如刀绞
Which really hurts because I bought her that phone.
我真是犯了一个大错
I made a huge mistake.
不  你没有做错
No, you didn't. Okay?
伯特  以前我有钱时
Look, Bert, when I had money,
我和好多不合适的女孩约会过
I dated lots of girls who weren't right for me.
后来我放弃了万贯家财  如今我孤身一人
And then I gave up my money,and now I'm alone
借宿在朋友家  拜托谁快点来把这个话头接走
and living with my friends,and somebody else should probably talk now.
亲  我说  恋爱并不是靠金钱维系的
Look, sweetie,relationships aren't about money, okay?
而是靠相互尊重和共同之处  以及...
It's about respect and having things in common and...
什么事  谢尔顿
Yes, Sheldon?
你和莱纳德就没有任何共同之处呀  也许你俩也该分手
You and Leonard don't have anything in common.Maybe you should break up.
你自己让他发言的
You called on him.
猜猜谁从托儿所回来啦
Guess who's home from day care?
是我们的小哈雷  除非有别人也在宝宝脚底做了X记号
It's Halley. Unless somebody else put an X on the bottom of their kid's foot.
你们一接走她  托儿所就给我打电话
You realize they called when you took her.
猜猜谁从水族馆回来啦
Guess who's home from the aquarium?
抱歉突然来打搅
Sorry again for barging in.
别走嘛  我们都很欢迎你一起玩
You don't have to go. You're welcome to hang with us.
事实上  我们的朋友小团体已经满员了
Actually, our friendship group is at capacity.
但如果有人退出  你将是第一候补团员
But if anybody drops out, you're at the top of the list.
除非是拉杰退出  那样的话  我们会需要补充一个有色人种
Unless it's Raj, in which case, we'll probably get a person of color.
你们人太好了  但是我准备买一台水上摩托
You guys are nice, but I'm just gonna buy Rebecca a Jet Ski
来唤回丽贝卡芳心
and see if that gets her back.
我真替伯特不值
I feel bad for Bert.
其实他用他的钱来吸引女性
So he's using his money to attract a mate.
和我用我的智慧来吸引艾米有什么不同吗
Is that any different than me using my intelligence to attract Amy?
莱纳德不也用他的卑躬屈膝去吸引佩妮吗
Or Leonard using his power of groveling to get Penny?
差别可太大了
It's totally different.
伯特的万贯家财有尽时  我的跪求大法无绝期
Bert's money might run out,but I can beg until the end of time.
不光如此  他还比我矮
All that and he's shorter than me.
谢尔顿  艾米有哪些地方吸引你
Sheldon, what did Amy have that attracted you?
数不胜数呀
Oh, so many things.
她聪慧的头脑  善良的品行  尤其是她绝妙的身体
Her mind, her kindness,and especially her body.
真的吗
Really?
别多想  我和他的血型一样  他知道我的器官可以捐给他
Relax. We're the same blood type.He knew he could harvest an organ.
她看起来挺开心的
She does look happy.
看到没  这才是对她好的选择  我们上班去吧
See? This is the right thing for her. Let's all just go to work.
想走时就吱一声
Anytime.
让我告别一下就好
Let me just say good-bye.
哈雷  看看妈咪
Halley. Look at Mommy.
我在这里呢  宝贝
Over here, honey.
跟你老妈说拜拜
Say good-bye to Mommy!
快看老娘  看一眼生你养你的亲妈呀
Look at me! Look at your mother!
好了  我们走吧
All right, we can go.
大家好  我是谢尔顿·库伯博士
Hello. I'm Dr. Sheldon Cooper.
我是艾米·法拉·福勒博士
And I'm Dr. Amy Farrah Fowler.
基于我们最近播出的《有趣的旗帜:  旗帜背后回忆特辑》反响非凡
Based on the glowing reception of our recent Behind the Flags retrospective,
我们想你们大概想看看它的制作过程
we thought you might like to see how it all came together.
欢迎收看今晚的特辑
So welcome to tonight's episode...
《有趣的旗帜: 旗帜背后回忆特辑的
Fun with Flags:Behind the Behind the Flags.
背后回忆特辑》
A Retrospective Retrospective.
已经有一位观众来电了
Ooh, we already have our first call.
您好  欢迎致电《有趣的旗帜》
Hello, you're on Fun with Flags.
水上摩托成功了  我的爱人又回来了
The Jet Ski worked. I got her back.